Jack Gallagher

2905 S. 18th Street #R St. Louis, MO 63118

Summary

A daily chess player. I have a natural desire for solving puzzles. After intensely studying Mandarin for 4 years, I found that my career options lacked a creative aspect that I desired. Computer science and web development captured my imagination. My eclectic background in different industries and experience working with different teams makes me a perfect candidate for a position in web development.

Technical Skills

Front End: html5, CSS, Bootstrap, Thymeleaf

Back End: Java 8, Springboot, Hibernate, MySQL, Python

Workflow: Git, Github, Agile process

Projects

Disc Golf Marketplace Web-app

Developed a web-app that allows users to buy and sell used disc golf discs called Flip.

- Java, Spring, Hibernate, Thymeleaf, MySQL, HTML, and CSS
- Aside from market capabilities, it utilizes Spring Security to allow for secure authentication to the web server
- Database persistence and table relational mapping were key in development
- github.com/jackpg09/flip

Education

LaunchCode 2018 - present

- 20 week program that focuses on programming fundamentals, web basics, and more advanced concepts with Java.
- Curriculum covered: Python, Flask, Jinja2, SQLAlchemy, MySQL, Java, Spring, Hibernate, and Thymeleaf
- Built multiple in and out of class projects

University of Missouri 2009-2013

- Bachelor of Arts International Studies (emphasis on Mandarin)
- Bachelor of Science International Business (emphasis on business administration)

Experience

Liftoff 2018

- Agile project management briefings
- Built a used disc golf disc marketplace application
- Collaborated with fellow students and teaching assistants in and outside of class

Green Leaf Procurement - 2017- Present

- Account Manager
 - Coordinate with regional businesses and provide support for online stores for promotional products and apparel.

Irreco - 2016 - 2017

- Operations Manager
 - Successfully led and organized several teams to effectively and efficiently perform various types of landscaping projects. Role involved "on the fly" strategic assessment of route efficiency, work type and team to enable time, gas, and monetary savings.